Hello.
Welcome back.
In this lesson, we are going to see how to use more to pull you out modules.
We've seen how to use you, too.
We use that to transmit to hello from Cuba, mix in our first you project.
And the previous one, we saw how to use a different you out module, which was you at one.
We created the R x t x loop back and we were able to use interrupt to send data from the T X to the
Erich's.
This time we're going to initialize to you auto modules and use interrupt with both of them.
So I'm going to come to connectivity over here.
And then on the other two, I'm going to set it up us over here, asynchronous mode and we can get our
you to hear.
And then I'm going to set you at one as well as asynchronous mode.
Right.
And then we have our you at one here and we're going to use interruptible both of them.
So this is you at one sentence.
We had a we at the end of acceptance.
OK.
Let's deal with this later.
Let's go and calibrate our clock to 60 megahertz SUDA all f four boards would have the same thing.
I'm going to change this to H.
S I up here and then I'll change over here to 16 hit enter.
And we all have 16.
Okay, so now come to pin conflagration or come to systems view and then I'll select you at or you saw
one once of clicked.
I would expand from here like this.
And I'll come to the end, Vic Certains.
Look at this.
I just drug this open, this is you start one.
This is the parameter set and we keep everything here the same.
We really don't want to change anything here.
It looks good.
We want a neighbor to interrupt.
So just a neighbor global interrupt here.
Right.
This for you saw one or two.
The same for you.
To know what to use that to when they were global.
Interrupt here.
Okay.
Once that is done, I'm going to generate my project.
I'm going to come over here.
And then I'll give the project a name.
Cohodas you at.
Multiple.
And then I'll select my two chain over here, which is the SDM 32 Kubi E.
And then I'll click here to generate the code.
So this my project of clean up some of the comment and the experiment here is gonna be similar to the
other one.
You can inspect the code.
As you can see now, we have you are 20, you are two of Sandos and both of them have been initialized.
And when we come to a wall in its function, we have you saw one in it.
Use us two in it.
Right.
OK, clean these comments over here to shorten the length of the file.
Clean this as well.
Hmm.
And then this.
Okay.
So I'm going to create my ah ex ante x buffer like I did earlier.
The T X has the data are X is empty and we expect to be able to get a data.
Oh.
So if we inspect our I.T. dot see file, we realize that we have uninterrupted request handler for use
out to us.
Well.
So we have you sought to either.
Q You saw one either are.
Q Because we enabled global interrupt for both of them.
I'm going to copy and paste the code from our previous use of the project.
We had the callback while you ought x complete callback and then we had how you got our X complete and
we had two global variables that we were using to count the number of T X and the number of our X,
so I've put out here.
So now the question becomes over here, the local parameter is h you at.
How do you know whether r x complete.
Okay.
Don't use that one.
Or use us two.
In the same way.
How do you know where the T X complete occurred on U.
S.
One or you said two and solved solve.
We can use an if statement to check if h you are T equals one then we no use that one completed.
If it was to then we know it's you said two.
So two.
Dennis, do you remember the um the you said this over here is a structure and the structure has different
members.
The member, the member that keeps the module name is known as the instance.
And this literally is the you are to register that base address as we see written here.
So we're gonna check the instance if the instance, because your attitude in that is you add to or you
said remember the word you utting use that are used interchangeably.
And I explain to you why these two words exist.
You know, Synchronoss, asynchronous by Fey using just the asynchronous is simply you, art.
Okay, so we're gonna check if the instance is of you ought to or you add or you add one and then we
take the appropriate action.
So I'm going to see over here if this logo over here, if this and then member instance, because it's
a pointer, we use the arrow operator if instance because to let's see, use that one.
What we want to do is.
To just put do we use that one related something so something specific you want for you said one and
then we can do.
Also, if I can copy this and put this over here, because you said to then you do you start to relate
it to something.
So you're working with two, you sort of mojos and you have a block of code that execute for the data
that, you know, is received from USA one.
And you have a different block of code to execute for the data that is received from USA two.
So you put that you saw to one in this, um, if block here and you put a user one in this block.
We can do the same.
We can actually copy exactly the same thing and then put it in our, you know, what we call it in our
T X and this global this is something that is outside the if statement.
This is just for the T x any such reception.
We can have something that will be executed, but if it's coming from use, that's one.
We can have something else that will execute.
Only when we receive from user that one.
And we can have another block of code that would execute.
Only when it's received from USA two.
So that is how our code looks currently.
So we can start a while.
You saw to it interrupt like we did earlier.
I'm just gonna paste those two lines here.
This is for start in.
Um, you said one hour breaks and then you start to use to one T X.
So we just taken a look.
I you saw one.
No.
Um, so if we run this, the results in the live expressions window should be exactly the same.
But we can make this a bit more interesting by starting use out to us.
Well.
But let's see, are we going to use the same buffer if we want to run the same experiment, the same
Loop Park experiment with you said to then we need to connect a jumper wire.
Uh, we need to connect the use said to our ex ante experience, just like we did for user one.
And then, um, we can do it.
So I'm just gonna copy this and then paste it here.
And then I'll change this to you.
Set two.
And then you set two here.
OK.
So we have this as well.
And then, um, what's gonna happen here is I'm gonna create another buffer here.
I'll copy this and then I'll call this T X buffer to T X buffer to here.
And then over here we simply Quint's and one to just single numbers.
OK.
Actually we'll be better if T x buffer one is the one that says single numbers.
So now of change.
I want T X buffer two one.
And then we have T X buffer one to X buffer to our X buffer one.
Our X buffer two.
And I'm going to change the data we are sending over here like this.
Okay.
And this was sent in okay.
Right.
So this if we run and we go and check out our X bar for one and our expert for two would see that they
would both receive the data.
We can create.
So this you can think of these, um, control variables.
There's global contessa's us just telling us what's on our X has arrived or T X.
Now let's create custom ones that will tell us specifically.
I use that one.
Our X arrived in the USA too.
So I'm going to have our X counter one over here.
And then T X counter one.
And then our X counter to T X Konta two.
So what I'm gonna do here is over here in my outer X, if it's from USA one, I'm going to count T X,
counter one.
And if it from two to X Konta to you like this.
And then in the Erich's I'm gonna do the same thing.
I'm going to add all of this to the live expression's window if it's from one one.
If it's from two to remember, this one just tells us that, you know, on our excess or kid, regardless
of whether it's one or two.
And this one is specificly for one and this one is specifically for two.
So let's go and run this current good currently.
I don't have a jumper connected to the R, X and T X of my use out two.
So we don't expect you sots to to count anything because there's nothing going on there.
After we've verified that X only is being shown to count, then we know the R X bar fights working and
then we add the um the other part for the, the um the to the user too.
So I'm gonna go ahead and build.
Let's see.
So over here.
So I'm going to change this.
We renamed this to buffer one before up before one over here and then before two and then two over here.
Okay.
So click over here to build.
It's building.
And then we go to debug by clicking over here.
Right.
So I'm going to remove this.
And then once I've removed it or add all of our new clothes.
OK.
Let's go up here.
Are you sure you want to remove this?
I want to remove from live expression or remove everything from here.
Remove all and then we go up.
We're going to take T, X Buffa one, OK, T X.
We know the content of T X, we need not check T X, so our X before one, which is for use that one.
Then we're going to go to our X counter one to see whether you know, you saw one received.
And then we going to go to um r x puffer too.
This is for you Saaz to remember currently you said to look back.
It's not connected of not connected.
A jumper wire for use are two.
So we don't expect to see anything transmitted and then we're going to do um counter to our X counter
to which will be for use out to our X counter to over here.
So I'm going to put this over here like this.
And then I'm going to put break point in my code in the while.
One loop inside here.
Point, break point.
And then I'll click here to run.
And then a click to run again.
And I can see are X.com to one has incremented to one.
And our X for one, it has the content.
One, two, three, four, five.
And our X buffer to has nothing is because we have not connected the Erickson T X line.
So nothing has been received.
So the essence of this is that we know that the our firmware can identify where the, um, the interrupt
kid wreck's counter want is just for use out one.
That is why we have this.
Okay.
In our X counter to nothing, OK.
It is still zero and then it's about five two zero.
So I'll live it up to you to connect to the jumper wires to connect our X are X and to X of sorts to.
We can verify that from here when we come to penult we know it's p a two MPLX three.
So all you have to do is go to our.
Our datasheet over here and find P a two and a three, so there's P a two MPLX through this P two,
P A three.
Actually, let's do that together so that we make sure there are no unforeseen problems.
Cos I've not tried this before, so I'm going to connect, not a jump away from P A to B A three.
I've already connected P in Olympia 10.
That is for the U at one.
Are we doing the same for you at two.
I've done my connection.
I'll minimize this or minimize this so we can um.
We can stop and then go back to debug.
You can see what we have.
Click over here.
It says, failed to evaluate our export for one.
So I'm going to remove that and put it back.
Sometimes this happens or remove this and our export for one again.
Where is it?
This is our X buffer one.
This is where they receive data from, you know, USD one will be stored.
So a new expression over here.
Hit enter.
And we still have our break point inside to you while one loop.
So click here to run and then I'll click again to run.
Let's see, we have our X counter too, which is those who are X counter one is one.
Let's see.
Why are X counter to sue?
But we can verify Eric's buffer to see what we have with our data.
Okay.
Nothing has changed here.
Let's see.
Right.
Okay.
So we're not seeing anything here.
And this could make sense because remember, our you ought to it's the same line that we use for debugging.
So perhaps the system is not allowing us to, um, sort of create a loop back using our.
Said to which is the same line that our debugger uses.
So, um, we can, um, we can stop this experiment.
A better experiment will be maybe to send a data from one use out to another, use it and check the
serial monitor whether we can see it.
Since you said to her success, to the, um, the internal USP to, uh, use that converter.
We can check what we send from user to want to use it to.
We can do the communication between the two.
Rather than apply the, um, the loop back method for user to as well.
And as we can all see from here, we know that, yes.
Our callback function recognizes.
Which you said happened just that.
Yeah.
The Lookback method over here.
This tricky method, perhaps it's not the best method for use out to because it has been used as I want
debug line as well.
And I hope you understand this.
So I'm gonna stop this.
But certainly you can try.
And if you see an anomaly as to why this is no, um, behave in a way should behave.
You can leave it in the Q&A section for all of us.
Yeah.
So what I'm going to do is I'm going to open the terminal and send some byte and see if we can receive
that to user two.
So everything is the same.
I'm not changing anything in the code.
I'm going to go to debug fuel over here.
It opened in.
And, um, all of these years failed to x, uh, to, um, fail to evaluate expression, so I'm gonna
remove all of that, remove all, and then, um, I'm going to go to our r x buffer to where is this
running someone else.
Look, uh.
Okay, here we go.
Cause I had the previous projects may not see file open as well.
And then, um, so are X Buffer to come over here at this hour, X two, which is for us.
You add to our exposure to copy controls each copy and then over here to paste and then I'll take the
counter as well.
Contrasty to copy and paste as well.
It says, cannot evaluate this.
Let's see.
I'm going to repeat what my project cost of this.
Come over here, remove or stop this.
For a bill, it's my project, I'm going to add X buffer to, again, our expert for to.
Controversy to copy that expression.
And then I'm going to add our X Coulter to controversy to copy.
Old expression.
So this is for you, sir, too.
I'm going to open terror to.
Click to open it, and I'm going to select my comport here.
I know you saw, too, is my S.T. link virtual COMPORTS or so like this?
I'll say.
Okay.
And then I'm going to go to set up to set the correct ball straight, cause the default here is no what
we set or select this then.
Okay.
And then I have my code run in.
I have the um I've not started running but a breakpoint is still inside the um the wall one loop.
Let's see.
This has to be opened.
This is it.
This outbreak points, so click here to run.
And it's run in a quick year to run.
And I'm simply going to type something into something is received here.
Um, we have something received.
And I just type something and you can see because I type something.
We have our X counter too, received here.
And let's see what I typed.
I just type some random stuff.
Right.
OK, so we are working with both user to a user want.
Now we can check out why you said one is still working.
It's not like it has stopped.
So I'm just going to copy this and add user to one X for two expressions just to show you that it's
still active as well.
And let's see if we can see you see that one is to send in the data.
That got sent.
Right.
And I want the reason why I wa.
Oh, are you sad, too?
It's not showing.
Well, we sent it because we no longer use in the T x profar for you said to remember.
We have taken out my loop back jumper wire so well Gore received in USA two is the random stuff that
I typed and we can see you saw it.
You said to counter showing that yes, we've received something.
OK.
So that's all to use to use out Mojo's.
And then, um, the um.
The lesson here is that in the callback you can basically use an if statement to um, to find which
you site has just transmitted or receive data and run the appropriate block of code to this or the rest.
I'll see you later.
Have a nice day.